Melissa M. Patterson

melizzap.github.io melissa.patterson.va@gmail.com 757.846.7853 Chicago, Il

Summary

After serving 4 years in the Air Force, I decided to switch gears and dive into something I've always been passionate about, programming. Since November 2014 I have dedicated my time growing as a software developer. As a junior developer I've had the opportunity to touch many different technologies. In my current position I'm a full stack developer using Angular on top of a rails application that queries elasticsearch. The best part about being in this industry is working with other like-minded developers who are eager to learn and build quality maintainable software.

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript, SQL, XML, HTML

Platforms and Frameworks: Rails, AngularJS, Elasticsearch, PostgreSQL, JQuery, Jasmine

Tools: Git, Jenkins, Jira

Experience

OpinionlabChicago, ILRails/JavaScript EngineerApril 2014-Present

• Develop web application using primarily Ruby on Rails, Angular, and Elasticsearch

• Part of a 5 person self-driven team practicing agile/scrum development

Help maintain and upgrade legacy comment card system built in XSL by implementing ES6

MakersquareAustin, TXStudentNov 2014-Feb 2015

- Full stack web application immersive aimed at developing JavaScript and Rails Engineers
- Headed a 5 person team in the development of an events application that was fully launched in 2 weeks. Rails backend and an Ember front end that are both completely self sufficient. The backend queries 3 APIs through threading to provide search data 3 times faster and delivers it via RESTful endpoints. The front end, displays the events on a map interface. https://github.com/remember-me
- Built a group playlist manager using Meteor and the Spotify API. Managed functionality of user interface, as well as communication with the Spotify API. Launched in 4 days https://github.com/lemurgency/music-snob.

Air Force Research Lab

Fort Sam-Houston, TX

Lead Laser Evaluation Physicist

Nov 2010 – Nov 2014

- Lead a seven member laser evaluation team with an annual budget of \$1.5M, managing laser safety for 33 programs, 200+ personnel and a \$50M facility.
- Collected and presented data on high energy laser backscatter studies at an international laser conference with 23 countries represented
- Performed over 30 on-site, in depth technical evaluations of complex laser systems.
- Purchase and maintain \$5.6M worth of research equipment, ensure all items are calibrated and appropriate for individual experiments.
- Developed and tested new ESRI based software for Air Force-wide implementation, replacing antiquated software and increasing accuracy by 26%.
- Engineered searchable database for all Air Force laser systems, a template other branches of the military have since emulated.
- Designed and built a device that redistributes high power laser energy making measurement two times faster and much safer by eliminating stray beams.
- Published 30 technical reviews and two studies for external customers.

Education

University of Virginia Bachelors - Physics Charlottesville, VA May 2010

Melissa M. Patterson

melizzap.github.io melissa.patterson.va@gmail.com 757.846.7853 Chicago, Il

Community Involvement

Meetup - Regular attendee of JavaScript and Ruby geared meetups

Science Mentor - at a local elementary school as part of an after school program. Every other week I would tutor grade schoolers in science.

Improv - Active member of the improv scene. Including a San Antonio based improv troupe that performed for many charity organizations, such as Rotary Youth Leaders of America and the Hydrocephalus Foundation